准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
啊
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
他们会在哪呢
Where could they be?
好几小时之前就该来了的
They should've been here hours ago
啊
Arrgh
蟹堡王
半个客人都见不到
Not a customer in sight
要是今天一分钱都赚不到
If I don't make any money today
我肯定会起疹子的
I'll surely break out in a rash
我发财了
I'm rich
派大星你看
Look, Patrick
八个金币
Eight gold doubloons
别动  我先看到的
Wait, I saw it first
我的  我的
Mine, mine
蟹老板  你出的汗真的好多
Boy, Mr. Krabs, you sure are sweaty
这什么东西
What's this?
金币在哪
Where are the doubloons?
这边没有真金币  蟹老板
There are no real doubloons, Mr. Krabs
这是款桌游
It's a game
飞天魔鬼大寻宝
The Flying Dutchman's Treasure Hunt
改编自真正的藏宝图
Based on a real treasure map
飞天魔鬼大寻宝
休息一下  跟咱玩几局
Take a break and play around with us
是啊
Yeah
来几局吧  流汗的
C'mon, sweaty
你擦完桌子了吗
Have you finished cleaning the tables?
擦完桌子了  蟹老板
I cleaned the tables, Mr. Krabs
擦完了没错  可底下的口香糖刮了吗
Aye, but did you scrape all the gum off the underside?
已经办妥了
I already took care of it
那好吧  小子们
All right, lads
看来你们把我拐进来了
Looks like you've shanghaied me
轮我了
My turn
五
Five
你有一个船友干了坏事
One of your shipmates has been a bad pirate
关他禁闭
Send him to the brig
你要坐牢去了  蟹老板
It's off to jail for you, Mr. Krabs
派大星  你被开除了
Patrick, you're fired
可我都没在这工作
But I don't even work here
你想不想要现在就开始工作
Would you like a job, starting now?
不会吧
Boy, would I?
你被开除了
You're fired
轮我了
My turn
一二三四
One, two, three, four
透过古树的树杈寻找执事的鹅
Look for the Deacon's Goose thru the fork in the old tree
然后朝那个方向走
and head that way
我看到蟹老板的裤链役拉
Well, I see Mr. Krabs' zipper is undone
真见鬼
Shiver me timbers
开玩笑而己  蟹老板
Just kidding, Mr. Krabs
我就快找到宝藏了
I'm almost to the treasure
轮你了蟹老板
Your turn again, Mr. Krabs
两个一
Fish eyes
一  二
One, two
你变成真正的海盗了
You are a real pirate
直接前往标有x的藏宝地点
Go straight to the "X" which marks the spot
你可以挖宝藏了  蟹老板
You get to dig for treasure, Mr. Krabs
宝藏
Treasure?
出现了
There it is
是飞天魔鬼的宝藏
It's the Flying Dutchman's Treasure
金子  金子
Gold, gold
我的  我的
Mine, mine
蟹老板又流好多汗出来了
Mr. Krabs is getting all sweaty again
快给烤架点火
Rev up those fryers
我饿得好想来一份
'cause I am sure hungry for one
救命
Help
蟹堡王
我的腿
My leg
看不出来我们关门了吗
Can't you see we're closed?
准备好要再来一局了吗
Ready for another round?
这游戏跟我很般配
This is my kind of game
蟹堡王
万岁
Hooray
六点
Six
一  二
One, two
我又赢了
I win again
连赢十七局了
That's 17 times in a row
我看我们还是到此为止吧  蟹老板
I think we ought to call it a night, Mr. Krabs
我真的得去睡觉了
I really got to get some sleep
你可不能现在就丢下我
You can't walk out on me now
对不起  蟹老板
I'm sorry, Mr. Krabs
明天再见
See you tomorrow
是谁在那
Who's there?
来吧  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
再来一局
One more game
我都能闻到宝藏的香气了
I can smell the treasure
蟹老板  都这么晚了
Mr. Krabs, it's late
睡觉去
Go to bed
晚安  蟹老板
Good night, Mr. Krabs
轻风和煦潮正顺
Wind is perfect, the tide is right
我们快去找宝藏
Let's hunt for treasure
蟹老板  你得
Mr. Krabs, you gotta
脚步放轻点  小子
Tread softly, lad
要是飞天魔鬼听到你声音
If the Dutchman hears you
他宝藏就到不了我们手上了
we'll never get his treasure
可是蟹老板
But, Mr. Krabs
骰子我帮你掷  小子
I'll roll for you, boy
可是蟹
But, Mr.
向北八步
8 paces, north
开局还真是不错  小子
That's a good start, lad
可是蟹
But, Mr.
一
One
二
Two
三
Three
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
我想去睡觉
I want to go to bed
蟹老板对不起
Mr. Krabs, I'm sorry
可你知不知道这只是个游戏
but it's just a game, ya know?
游戏
A game
那倒
That's
确实
right
确实是这样  我的错
Of course it is, my mistake
我应该是沉迷过头了  对吧
I guess I got a little carried away, eh?
虽然咱在这玩的时光确实珍贵如宝藏
Though it is treasure we're dealing here
抱歉打扰到你了  小子
Sorry, for disturbing ya, lad
停航
Avast
抵达菠萝屋
Pineapple, ho
停下  准备登船
Heave to, and prepare to be boarded
快回家行不
Go home already
我不玩那个游戏了  蟹老板
I'm done playing that game, Mr. Krabs
跟你讲话的是蟹船长
That’s Captain Krabs to you
而且这不是游戏
and this is no game
我们要当海盗
We're gonna be pirates
海盗
Pirates?
没错
Aye
想不想要来一场真正的寻宝冒险
How'd you like to go on a real treasure hunt
用真正的藏宝图
with a real treasure map?
宝藏
Treasure?
我们要当海盗了
We're gonna be pirates
别跳了
Belay that skipping
海盗是不跳的
Pirates don't skip
穿上这身海盗服
Put on this pirate garb
这样我被你们看到才不会觉得尬
so I won't be embarrassed to be seen with ya
啊
Arrgh
派大星你看
Patrick, look
假腿跟眼罩
Peg legs and eye patches
现在你们是不是更有海盗的感觉了
Now, don't you feel more like pirates?
快看  我是假腿海盗
Look, I'm Peggy the Pirate
我是瞎胡子海盗
I'm Blindbeard the Pirate
啊
Arrgh
严格戒备  海绵宝宝
Keep a sharp lookout, SpongeBob
根据地图上写的
According to the map
我们正在接近第一个地标
we're close to the first landmark
真的吗
Really?
我们能看地图吗
Can we see the map?
不能
No
只有船长才可以看地图
Only the captain can lay eyes on the map
好了啦
Okie dokie, then
啊
Arrgh
海盗才不会说什么
A pirate doesn't say
好了啦
"okie dokie, then"
海盗要说
A pirate says
啊
"arrgh"
好
Okie
我是说
I mean
啊  蟹船长
Arrgh, Captain Krabs
船长  我们就要触
Captain, we're about to hit
我是说
I mean
啊  船长
Arrgh, Capt.
啊  我们
arrgh, we're
啊  就要
arrgh, about
啊  触
arrgh, to hit
啊
arrgh
有话直说  啊
Out with it man, arrgh
我  啊
I, arrgh
觉得  啊
think, arrgh
他要  啊
he's trying, arrgh
说
to say
着陆了
land
啊
Arrgh
从现在起  只有船长才能说啊
From now on, only the captain says, arrgh
报告状态  海绵宝宝先生
Status report, Mr. SquarePants?
整艘船都在水底下了  船长
The whole ship is underwater captain
啊
Arrgh
我们被困了
We're marooned then
我们的接下来的寻宝之旅必须步行了
Our treasure hunt will have to continue on foot
到了  小子们
This is it, boys
从双叶海草的位置
from the seaweed with 2 leaves on it
向东10000步
10,000 paces east
可是  蟹老板
But, Mr. Krabs
这海草有
That seaweed has
向哪走  船长
Which way, cap'n?
派大星少尉  哪边是东
Ensign Patrick, which way is east?
我看下
Let's see
北
西
东
南
那边  船长
That way, captain
9,997
9,998
9,999
1,0000
x哪去了
Where's the "X"?
应该就在这的啊
Supposed to be right here
向东10000步
10,000 paces east
向东吗
East?
我还以为你说的是  西东
I thought you said "weast"
西东
Weast?
你这看的什么指南针  小子
What kind of compass you reading, lad?
就这个  长官
This one, sir
那叫向西  派大星
That's west, Patrick
西
你又被开除了
You're fired again
9,551
9,552
蟹老板  我们好累
Mr. Krabs, we're tired
还好饿
And hungry
所以说我的船员就这水平
So this is my crew
你们就累一点
You get a little tired
饿一丢丢
and a wee bit hungry
然后你们就想走人回家去了
and you want to shove off for home
啊
Arrgh
恶心死我了
That sickens me
不能靠短剑上的刻痕来评价一个海盗
A pirate is not judged by the notches in his cutlass
也不能靠战利品大小来评价一个海盗
or by the size of his booty
要靠船员的忠诚度来评价一个海盗
A pirate is judged by the loyalty of his crew
没了忠诚的船员
And without a loyal crew
我当船长指挥什么
what am I captain of?
一堆散沙罢了
Just a bunch of sand
别哭了  蟹船长
Don't cry, Captain Krabs
对  我们会当好你的忠诚船员的
Yeah, we'll be your loyal crew
那你们要跟我留下来吗
You'll stay with me then?
我们会当好史上最忠诚的海盗船员的
We'll be the most loyal pirate crew ever
我就知道你们靠得住  小子
I knew I could count on you boys
我为人人
One for all
人人为我
And all for one
我好忠诚
I'm so loyal
忠诚到都不介意
I don't even mind
自己睡在又冷又硬的地上
sleeping on the cold, hard ground
蟹船长却睡在暖和干燥的帐篷里
while Captain Krabs sleeps in his warm, dry tent
我忠诚到好几周都没洗澡了
I'm so loyal, I haven't bathed in weeks
可我们才刚走几小时而已
But we've only been gone a few hours
这我知道
I know
我忠诚到
I'm so loyal
找不到宝藏就不睡觉
I don't wanna sleep till we find the treasure
我们去看下船长要不要出发
Let's see if the captain will go now
蟹船长
Captain Krabs?
他不在
He's not here
快看
Look
是藏宝图
The treasure map
只有船长才可以看地图  派大星
Only the captain can look at the map, Patrick
确实
Yeah
派大星  你在搞什么
Patrick, what are you doing?
没什么
Nothing
派大星  不能看地图的
Patrick, you're not supposed to look at the map
我没看  这是在摸
I'm not looking, I'm touching
没有规定说不可以这样的  对吧
There's no rule against that, is there?
确实  应该没有
No, guess there isn't
派大星  它自己展开了
Patrick, it opened by itself
地图
The map
我要看一眼
I gotta see it
我得瞧一眼
Gotta look at it
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
怎么了
Yeah?
你有没有注意到地图有什么熟悉的地方
Did you notice something familiar about this map?
比如说
You mean, like
藏宝图是拿咱桌游贴到一张纸上做的
that it's our game board taped to a piece of paper?
你们觉得这成大问题吗
Do you think this is a problem?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
居然偷看我藏宝图
Sneaking peeks at me treasure map?
对不起
We're sorry
这是我船上发生的叛变
That's mutiny on my ship
所以你们是不是觉得蟹船长发疯了
So you think ol' Captain Krabs has gone crazy, do ye?
完全不是的  蟹船长
Not at all, Captain Krabs
我们完全没觉得你疯
We don't think that at all
是我觉得你疯
I think that
我要把你们扔下海作为说错话的惩罚
I'm gonna throw you overboard for saying that
快看
Look
是x
It's the "X"
标x的是藏宝地点
"X" marks the spot
飞天魔鬼大寻宝
这游戏还真是改编自真正的藏宝图
That game really is based on a real treasure map
那你们还等什么  小子们
Well, what are you waiting for, lads?
挖
Dig
挖到了  蟹船长
We got it, Captain Krabs
把它交给我  小子们
Hand it up to me, lads
拉
Heave
总算找到了
We finally found it
飞天魔鬼的宝藏
The Dutchman's Treasure
你要用你分到的那份做什么  派大星
What are you gonna do with your share, Patrick?
不知道
I don't know
你要怎么花你分到的那份  海绵宝宝
How are you going to spend your share, SpongeBob?
分什么分
What shares?
我的宝藏你们都不准拿
You're not getting any of my treasure
那是我们一起找到的
We found it together
所以我们应该要分到一份
So we deserve a share
我是船长
Well, I'm the captain
我说这是我的
And I say it's mine
那么忠诚呢
What about loyalty?
人人为我
All for one
我为人人
And one for all
人人为我
All for one
我为人人
And one for all
人人为我
All for one
我是飞天魔鬼
I'm the Flying Dutchman
我为人人
And one for all
我是飞天魔鬼
I'm the Flying Dutchman
是谁胆敢吵醒飞天魔鬼
Who dares wake the Flying Dutchman?
能不能给我小点声
Keep it down will ya?
我要睡觉
I'm trying to get some sleep
人人为我
All for one
我为人人
And one for all
是谁把飞天魔鬼的宝藏挖出来的
Who dug up the Dutchman's treasure?
他们
They did
啊
Arrgh
所以是你们俩讨厌鬼把我宝藏挖出来的
So you two scallywags dug up me treasure?
你们省了我不少挖坑的工夫
Well, you saved me a lot of diggin' you did
因此这是给你们两个的奖励
So here's an reward for the two of ya's
两个金币
Two gold doubloons
等等
Wait
我可是这伙船员的船长
I'm captain of this crew
我的奖励在哪
Where's my reward?
我看你说得在理
I guess you're right
麻烦你了  一点点小意思给你
A little something for your trouble
金子  金子
Gold, gold
就只是个塑料做的小宝箱
Why, it's just a little plastic treasure chest
塑料
Plastic
没错
Aye
不过这可是照着真正的宝箱改编的
but it's based on a real treasure chest
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
你又流好多汗出来了
You're looking all sweaty again
石头滩
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
又是在手套乐园度过的欢乐一天
Another funtastic day at Glove World
手套乐园
我来拿下钱包
Let me get my wallet
等会
Wait
我找下这个口袋
let me check this pocket
没有
No
派大星  有没有零钱
Patrick, do you have any change?
要多少零钱
How much do you need?
要多少钱
How much is it?
五毛
Fifty cents
没有
Nope
我再找下另一个口
Let me check my other poc-
不用了
Forget it
你说什么
What did you say?
找位子坐好就行
Just take your seat
谢谢先生
Thanks, mister
行了  随
Yeah, whatev-
手套乐园
看下你在手套乐园买了什么
Show me what you got at Glove World
好
Okay
这是我的手套灯
Here's my glove light
我看到你了
I see you
我给我的手套手办买了手套
I got gloves for my glove action-figure
好酷
Cool
您正在
驶出裤头村
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob?
怎么了  派大星
Yeah, Patrick?
驶出裤头村是个什么地方
Where's 'Leaving Bikini Bottom'?
你哪看到的
Where did you see that?
刚路过了个路标
We just passed the sign
您已进入驶出裤头村
'You are now in Leaving Bikini Bottom'
什么
What?
怎么了  海绵宝宝
What's wrong, SpongeBob?
裤头村界
派大星  我们应该是搭错
Patrick, I think we're on the wrong
车了
bus
可是司机  我们得回裤头村去
But, sir, we need to get back to Bikini Bottom
对了
Oh, well
这啥玩意  海绵宝宝
What is this, SpongeBob?
石头滩
Rock Bottom
公较总占
这边真是好诡异
It sure is weird around here
有点不对劲
Kinda different
连土都看起来不对劲
even the soil looks different
介不
Would you
介意
mind
放我下来
putting me down?
海绵宝宝  我不喜欢这里
SpongeBob, I don't like it here
好黑好可怕
It's dark and scary
我不想待在这
I don't wanna be here
我想回家
I wanna go home
看
Look
我都分不清男女厕所了
I can't even tell the bathrooms apart
则所
很简单的  派大星
That's an easy one, Patrick
等人出来就能分得清男女厕所了
Just wait for someone to come out and then you'll know
女的吗
A lady?
或许应该再等一个人出来
Maybe we should wait for one more
我还是不懂牌子写的啥
I still can't read the sign
我想回家
I wanna go home
好
Okay
你来等公交
You wait for the bus
公交来了叫我一声
Call me when it comes
我要去拿公交时刻表
I'm gonna get a bus schedule
老天爷啊  这地方真的好可怕
Boy, this place sure is creepy
海绵宝宝  车来了
Hey, SpongeBob, the bus is here
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我看海绵爷爷说得对
I guess Grandpa SquarePants was right
不要追公交车
Don't run for a bus
特别是爬上90度坡的公交车
Especially one that's going up at a 90-degree angle
我最好去等下一辆
I better go wait for the next one
公较
公交快来
C'mon, bus
我得回家去喂小蜗
I've got to get home and feed Gary
鞋带松了
Shoe's untied
绕下去
Under
再绕上去
and over
再绕个圈
and loop-dee-loop
再绕上去
and over
再穿过口子
and through the barrel
我的气球
My balloon
别走
Wait
等等
Hold on
快停车
Stop that bus
又来了
Not again
不好意思  先生
Excuse me, sir
能帮我个忙吗
Can you help me?
没错我
Yeah, I
不
No
我说的不是气球
Not the balloon
我要知道下一班车什么时候来
I need to know when the next bus comes
又开走了一辆
Well, there goes another one
我得再好好等下去
I gotta be more diligent
无论如何我都不会离开这半步
I am not leaving this spot no matter what
饿了
Gettin' hungry
手套糖果袋
Glove candy dispenser
还好我去了手套乐园
Good thing I went to Glove World
手套味的
Glove flavored
那啥东西
What's that?
唐果
糖果售卖机
A candy machine
海草牛轧糖
Kelp nougat crunch
无论如何我都不会离开这半步
I'm not leaving this spot no matter what
只走开一小会
I'll only be gone a second
等等
Wait
海草
快点
Come on
那个是我的
That was mine
该死
Barnacles
行  都够了
Alright, that's it
不当好人了
No more mister nice guy
真该死
Tartar sauce
死混账
Fish paste
我倒要搞清这车怎么开的
I'm getting to the bottom of this, right now
公较总占
我要一趟回裤头村的车
I want a bus to Bikini Bottom
我排第一个  谁都不准瞎扯淡
I am first in line and no one is gonna tell me otherwise
行  排第二
Okay, second
我排第二个
I am second in line
行  第三挺好
Okay, third is good
第四不错
Fourth, not bad
行  329
Okay, 329
我排第329个  都给我记牢了
I am 329th in line and nobody forget it
下一个
Next
至少队伍在动
Well, at least the line is moving
真该死
Tartar sauce
下一个
Next
终于啊
Finally
没错我就是下一个
Yes, I'm next
去裤头村的下一班车什么时候开
When is the next bus to Bikini Bottom?
什么
What?
问讯处
公交时刻表
The bus schedule
下一班车
The next bus
我听
I can't
不懂
understand
你的口音
your accent
下一班
The next bus
到裤头村
to Bikini
的车
Bottom
问讯处
你咋不早说
Why didn't you say so?
下一班车
Next bus leaves in
五秒后开
5 seconds
问讯处
真倒霉  孩子
Tough luck, kid
那辆是晚上的最后一班车
That's the last one til' morning
不
Oh
行
no
别这样
you don't
晚安
Good night
关
别走  我还没说完
Hold it, I'm not through here
听见没有
Do you hear me?
你必须给我回来
I demand you come back
给我现在就来一趟到裤头村的车
and give me a bus to Bikini Bottom right now
你要不来  我就不走
Until then, I am not leaving this spot
行吧  就像我说的那样
Okay, like I said
你回来那会儿  我会在这好好等你的
I'll be right here when you get back
就在这
At this spot
一片黑
In the dark
就自己
By myself
孤身一人
With no one around
幸好还有手套灯陪我
Except my glove light
好多了
That's better
这不是一般的黑
This isn't your average everyday darkness
这是
This is
高级黑
advanced darkness
要是闭上眼睛就不会这么黑了
If I close my eyes, it doesn't seem so dark
是谁
Who's there?
反正总站明天也会在那
Well, I guess that spot will be there tomorrow
最好得一直走下去
I better just keep walking
跑
Running
最好开始跑
Better start running
跑
Running
狂奔
Sprinting
对  我最好得狂奔下去
Yes, I just gotta keep sprinting
坐下去
Sitting
讨厌
Bleeding
是谁
Who's there?
行了  都够了
Okay, that's enough
不要靠过来
Don't come closer
我警告你
I'm warning you
我可是海绵
I'm a sponge
原来只是你
It's only you
好啦  气球的问题是解决了
Well, that solves my balloon problem
可我还有个更严重的问题
but I have a bigger problem
我有点被困在这了
I'm kinda stuck here
要赶公交回家去
I need to catch a bus to get home
你是不是听不懂我说的话
You don't understand a word I'm saying, do you?
气球
Balloon
的
has
气
enough
够了
air
谢谢
thanks
我明白了  坐气球回去
I get it, balloon travel
谢谢
Thank
你
you
不客气
You're welcome
正在进入
石头滩
可算回家了
Home at last
放心好了  海绵宝宝
Don't worry, SpongeBob
我回来救你了
I'm coming back for ya